<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="array_bites_problem">
        <item>Snake Bites</item>
        <item>Spider Bites</item>
        <item>Bee and Wasp stings</item>
        <item>Jelly sting</item>
        <item>Animal Bites</item>

    </string-array>


    //snake bite
 <string name="bites_about_content">
There are 2 types of snake bites:\n\n
<b>DRY Bite</b> - where the snake injects no venom to its victim. The common symptoms include:\n
&#8226;Mild pain at the site of the bite caused by physical punctures by snake\'s fangs.\n
&#8226;Feeling of unease.\n
&#8226;Usually there are no other symptoms such as swelling.\n
&#8226;However the casualty should still visit the hospital for check up.\n\n

     <b>VENOMOUS Bite</b> - where the snake injects venom to it\'s victim. The common symptom include:\n
&#8226;Swelling and redness at the site of the bite, spreading up the bitten limp.\n
&#8226;Nausea.\n
&#8226;Vomiting.\n
&#8226;Blurred vision.\n
&#8226;Itchy rash on the skin.\n
&#8226;Numbness in face and limbs.\n
&#8226;Sweating and salivation.\n
&#8226;Breathing difficulties with wheezing.\n
&#8226;Irregular heartbeat.\n
&#8226;Confusion and dizziness.    </string>

    <string name="bites_priority">
        <u>Priority</u>

    </string>

    <string name="bites_priority_content">
   &#8226;Prevent the spread of venom in the body.\n
   &#8226;Transfer the casualty to hospital as soon as possible.
    </string>
    <string name="bites_treatment_content">
   &#8226; Advice the casualty to remain calm and cautiously move him or her away from the snake\'s striking distance.\n\n
&#8226; Help the casualty to remove any jewelry and any tight clothing from the area that was bitten before the wound starts swelling.\n\n
&#8226; If possible help the casualty to lie down with the wound below the heart.\n\n
&#8226; Keep the casualty a rest and as still as possible to prevent the venom from spreading.\n\n
&#8226; Clean the wound, but do not flush with water, after which cover it with a clean, dry dressing.\n\n
&#8226;  <b>DO NOT</b> apply ice or cut the wound in an attempt to remove the venom.\n\n
&#8226; <b>DO NOT</b> attempt to suck out the venom.\n\n
&#8226; <b>DO NOT</b> give the patient any alcoholic or caffeine drink because this can speed up the rate at which the body absorbs the venom.\n\n
&#8226; <b>DO NOT</b> attempt to capture the snake, instead take note of its features such as colour and shape, so that you can describe it to the medics.\n\n
&#8226; Help the casualty to remove their shoes if leg or feet was bitten.\n\n
&#8226; Seek for medical help as soon as possible.\n\n\n


    </string>


    //spider bites

    <string name="spider_recognition_content">
  General symptoms of bites from black widow and brown recluse spider:\n
&#8226;Fever.\n
&#8226;Vomiting.\n
&#8226;Nausea.\n
&#8226;Headache.\n
&#8226;Abdominal pain.\n
&#8226;Pain and redness on the site of the bite.\n
&#8226;Joint pain or stiffness.\n
&#8226;Muscle cramping.

    </string>


    <string name="spider_priority_content">
  &#8226;Get medical assistance.\n
&#8226;Treat symptoms relating to the spider bites\n
&#8226;If possible, kill the spider and giv it to the medical team.

    </string>
    <string name="spider_treatment_content">
  &#8226; Wash the wound with soap and water.\n\n
&#8226;Apply ice pack over the site of the bite.\n\n
&#8226;OCT- (over-the-counter) pain relievers may be used to relieve symptoms
        but aspirin should not be given to children instead use ibuprofen.\n\n
&#8226;Seek emergency treatment if the casualty is a young child and if you
        think the bite might be from poisonous spider e.g. black widow,
        if any sign of allergic reaction occurs, if site of bite becomes infected,
        if the casualty develops skin rashes or severe illness.\n\n
&#8226;If possible carry the spider along with you to the medics to be accurately identified.\n\n
&#8226;The casualty may be given a tetanus booster shot depending on the date of last immunization.\n\n

 </string>


    //bee sting

    <string name="bee_recognition_content">
  When you experience the following symptoms of severe allergic reaction to the sting,
        immediately seek for medical help. The symptoms include:\n
&#8226;Itching in areas of the body not affected by the sting.\n
&#8226;Breathing difficulties.\n
&#8226;Dizziness.\n
&#8226;Light headedness.\n
&#8226;Vomiting\n
&#8226;Nausea.\n
&#8226;Stomach cramps.\n
&#8226;Diarrhea.\n
&#8226;Skin rash.\n
&#8226;Severe swelling of face, lips or the throat.

    </string>


    <string name="bee_priority_content">
  &#8226;Remove the sting from the victim as quickly as possible.
&#8226;Limit swelling and pain.\n
&#8226;Immediately seek medical
        assistance if the victim is allergic to the sting or has multiple stings.

    </string>


    <string name="bee_treatment_content">
        The below steps can be applied to both bee and wasp stings:\n\n
 &#8226;Move the victim to a safe area to avoid more stings.\n\n
 &#8226;Immediately remove the stingers by brushing or scraping sideways e.g. by use of a credit card.
        <b>Never</b> pull out the sting as more venom will be injected causing more damage.\n\n
 &#8226;Apply to the site of the sting cloth filled with ice or dampened with cold water
        for 20 minutes once every hour as needed. This will help to provide mild relief.\n\n
 &#8226;Wash the sting site with soapy water as this will help neutralize the sting.\n\n
 &#8226;Taking antihistamine such as Banadryl will help with itching and swelling.\n\n
 &#8226;Take  <b>OTC</b> (over-the-counter) pain relievers such as ibuprofen to relieve some pain as needed.\n\n
 &#8226;The victim may be given a tetanus booster shot depending on the date of last immunization.
        If it has been more than 10 years, get the booster.\n\n
 &#8226;If you have multiple stings, if allergic or have severe reaction in the past when stung, please seek for medical help.\n\n
 &#8226;If you have a single sting and are not allergic to it, home treatment may be enough.\n\n
    </string>



    //jelly sting

    <string name="jelly_recognition_content">
When the victim experiences the following symptoms of severe allergic reactions to the sting,
        immediately seek for medical help. The symptoms include:\n
&#8226;Headache.\n
&#8226;Breathing difficulties.\n
&#8226;Dizziness.\n
&#8226;Light headedness and general body weakness.\n
&#8226;Vomiting.\n
&#8226;Nausea.\n
&#8226;Fever.\n
&#8226;Diarrhea.\n
&#8226;Skin rash.\n
&#8226;Loss of consciousness.\n
&#8226;Abnormal heart rate or chest pain.\n\n

<b>See the doctor when:\n\n</b>
&#8226;The victim has severe allergic reactions.\n
&#8226;The sting is from a box jellyfish.\n
&#8226;The stings cover a large area of the skin.
    </string>


    <string name="jelly_priority_content">
 &#8226;Help the victim to move away from the site of the sting e.g. sea water.\n
&#8226;Relieve pain.\n
&#8226;Seek for medication if necessary.

    </string>


    <string name="jelly_treatment_content">
       General first aid procedures for jellyfish sting include:\n\n
&#8226;If still in the sea, cautiously help the victim to move away from the water.\n\n
&#8226;Remove any pieces of jellyfish on the victim\'s skin by rinsing he skin with sea water gently
        scrap off the stingers using edges of a credit card. <b>DO NOT</b> wash the sting area
        with fresh water as it may activate more stingers.\n\n
&#8226;Rinse site of the sting with vinegar for about 30 seconds or apply baking soda paste.\n\n
&#8226;Apply ice packs on the site of the sting or hot (ranging between 40-45 degree centigrade\'s)
        for about 30 minutes ensuring it is not so hot that it can damage the skin, this will help ease pain.\n\n
&#8226;Take <b>OTC</b> (over-the-counter) pain reliever as this will also help to kill the pain.\n\n
&#8226;Apply lotions such as calamine or lidocaine or oral antihistamine to help relieve itching and discomfort.\n\n\n
    </string>


    //animal bite
    <string name="dog_priority_content">
 Seek urgent medical attention when:\n
&#8226;The wound is a deep puncture and are not sure how serious it is.\n
&#8226;The skin is badly injured and bleeding severely.\n
&#8226;You are not aware of the immunization status (against rabies) of the animal that bit you.\n
&#8226;When there is increasing swelling and redness at the site of the injury.\n
&#8226;When you haven\'t had a tetanus shot foe a long time e.g. the past five years.
    </string>


    <string name="dog_treatment_content">
  &#8226;If the bite did not break the skin and there is no risk of rabies,
        wash the wound with soap and water then apply antibiotic cream to prevent infection.
        Cover the site of the bite with a clean bandage.\n\n
&#8226;If the skin is badly torn and bleeding, apply pressure on the injured area using a dry clean
        cloth to prevent further bleeding,
        after which you should seek for medical assistance.\n\n\n
    </string>

</resources>