<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="array_cpr1_problem">
        <item>General CPR Tips</item>
        <item>Adult CPR</item>
        <item>Child CPR</item>
        <item>Infant CPR</item>
        <item>Recovery Position</item>
    </string-array>

    //general cpr tips
    <string name="cpr_general">
        <u>  CPR categories include:</u>
    </string>

    <string name="cpr_general_content">

&#8226; <b>Untrained</b> - If you are not trained in CPR, then provide hands-only CPR. That is,
        uninterrupted chest compression of about 100 times a minute until the medical team arrives.\n\n
&#8226;<b>Trained</b> - If you are well trained and confident in your ability,
        begin with about 30 chest compression before checking the airway and giving rescue breaths.\n\n
&#8226;<b>Trained but rusty</b> - If you have previously received CPR training
        but not confident in your abilities, then just do chest compression at a rate of about 100 times a minute.\n\n\n

    </string>


    //adult cpr tips
    <string name="adultcpr_about_content">
       Allways use the acronym <b>CAB</b> - Compression, Airway Breathing recommended by American Heart Association,
        to easily remember the steps for performing <b>CPR</b>.\n\n
     <b>NOTE</b>: If alone with the victim, perform <b>CPR</b> for about 2 minutes which consists of about 5 cycles of 30
        chest compression and 2 breaths each before calling your local emergency number.\n\n
    </string>


    <string name="adultcpr_compression">
        <u>Compression</u>

    </string>


    <string name="adultcpr_compression_content">
 &#8226;Place the victim on a firm surface on his or her back.\n\n
&#8226;Kneel next to the victim\'s neck and shoulders.\n\n
&#8226;Place the heal of one hand over the center of the person\'s chest between the nipples.\n\n
&#8226;Place your other hand on top of the fires hand and keep your elbows straight and position your shoulders directly above your hands.\n\n
&#8226;Use your upper body weight and not just your arms as you push straight down on the chest approximately 5 centimeters.\n\n
&#8226;Push hard at a rate of about 100 compressions a minute.\n\n
&#8226;If you are not trained in performing CPR continue with the chest compression until you see
        signs of movement or until the emergency medical team arrives.\n\n
&#8226;If you are trained in <b>CPR</b>, go on to checking the airway and rescue breathing.\n\n

    </string>

    <string name="adultcpr_airway">
         <u>Airway</u>
    </string>

    <string name="adultcpr_airway_content">
&#8226;If you are trained in performing <b>CPR</b> and have performed 30 chest compressions, put your
        palm on the person\'s forehead and gently
        tilt the head back. Then with the other hand, gently lift the chin forward to open the airway.\n\n
&#8226;Check for normal breathing for about 10 seconds on your cheek and ears.
        Grasping should not be considered to be normal breathing.\n\n
&#8226;If the victim is still not breathing normally and you are trained in <b>CPR</b> then begin mouth-to-mouth breathing.
        If untrained skip the mouth-to-mouth breathing and continue with chest compression.\n\n
    </string>


    <string name="adultcpr_breathing">
         <u>Breathing</u>
    </string>

    <string name="adultcpr_breathing_content">
&#8226;Rescue breathing can be mouth to mouth or mouth to nose if the victim\'s mouth is seriously injured or cannot be opened.\n\n
&#8226;With the air way opened, pinch the nostrils shut for mouth to mouth breathing and cover the person\'s mouth with yours making a seal.\n\n
&#8226;Prepare to give 2 rescue breaths. The first breath last for about 1 second and observe the chest to see whether it rises.\n\n
&#8226;If it does not rise, give the second rescue breath.\n\n
&#8226;Resume chest compression to restore circulation.\n\n
&#8226;If the victim has not begun moving after 5 cycles an Automated External Defibrillator <b>(AED)</b> can be used.\n\n
&#8226;If the <b>AED</b> is not available, continue with <b>CPR</b> until the victim shows signs of movement or the emergency medical team arrives.\n\n\n
</string>



    //child cpr
    <string name="childcpr_treatment_content">
        <b>The steps for giving CPR to a child aged 1-8 years are the same as that of adults except for
            the following differences:\n\n</b>

&#8226;Perform 5 cycles of compressions and breaths on the child for about 2 minutes.\n\n
&#8226;Call your local emergency number.\n\n
&#8226;Use only one hand to perform the chest compression.\n\n
&#8226;When performing Rescue Breaths, breathe more gently.\n\n
&#8226;Perform 30 compressions followed by 2 breaths which makes one cycle.\n\n
        This compressions-breath rate I the same as is used in adults. After the 2 breaths, immediately begin the next cycle.\n\n
&#8226;After the 5 cycles of the CPR and there is no response from the victim an AED can be used.\n\n
&#8226;If the AED is not available, continue with CPR until the victim shows the
        signs of movement or the emergency medical team arrives.\n\n\n
</string>



    //infant cpr tips
    <string name="infantcpr_about_content">
      Use the acronym <b>CAB</b> - Compression, Airway, Breathing to easily remember the steps for performing CPR.
<b>NOTE:</b> If alone with the victim, perform CPR for about 2 minutes which consists of about
        5 cycles of 30 chest compression and 2 breaths each before calling your local emergency number.\n\n
    </string>


    <string name="infantcpr_compression_content">
 &#8226;Place the baby on a firm, flat surface e.g. a table or floor.\n\n
&#8226;Imagine a horizontal line drawn between the baby\'s nipples.\n\n
&#8226;Place 2 fingers of one hand just below the imaginary line, in the centre of the chest.\n\n
&#8226;Gently compress the chest about 4 centimeters at a rate of 100 compressions a minute.\n\n
    </string>


    <string name="infantcpr_airway_content">
&#8226;If you are trained in performing CPR and have performed 30 chest compressions,
        put your palm on the baby\'s forehead and gently tilt the head back. \n\n
        Then with the other hand, gently lift the chin forward to open the airway.\n\n
&#8226;Check for normal breathing for about 10 seconds on your cheek and ears.\n\n
&#8226;If the victim is still not breathing normally and you are trained in CPR then begin mouth-to-mouth breathing.
        If untrained skip the mouth-to-mouth breathing and continue with chest compression.\n\n</string>


    <string name="infantcpr_breathing_content">
&#8226;Cover the baby\'s mouth and nose with your mouth.\n\n
&#8226;Prepare to give 2 rescue breaths. The first breath last for about 1 second.
        When giving the breaths, use the strength of your cheeks to deliver gentle puffs
        of air to slowly breath into the baby\'s mouth, instead of deep breaths from your lungs.\n\n
&#8226;Observe to see whether the chest rises, if it does not rise, give the second rescue breath.\n\n
&#8226;Resume chest compression to restore circulation.\n\n
&#8226;<b>DO NOT</b> use an AED for children younger than 1 year.\n\n
&#8226;Continue with CPR until the victim shows signs of movement or the emergency medical team arrives.\n\n\n</string>




    //recovery position


    <string name="cpr_recovery">
        <u>Recovery position procedure</u>

</string>

    <string name="cpr_recovery_content">
A person who is unconscious but is breathing and has no other life threatening condition,
        should be placed in the recovery position but if you think the person has a spinal injury,
        do not attempt to move them until the emergency medical team arrives. The steps are as follows:\n\n
&#8226;With the victim lying on their back, kneel on the floor at their side.\n\n
&#8226;Place the arm nearest to you at a right angle to the body, with their hand upwards towards the head.\n\n
&#8226;Tuck their other hand under the side of their head, so that the back of their hand is touching their cheek.\n\n
&#8226;Bend the knee farthest from you to a right angle.\n\n
&#8226;Carefully roll the victim onto their side by pulling on the bent knee.\n\n
&#8226;The top arm should be supporting the head and the bottom arm will support you rolling them too far.\n\n
&#8226; their airway by gently tilting their head back and lifting their chin.\n\n
&#8226;Stay with the victim and monitor their condition until the medics arrive at the scene.\n\n\n</string>




</resources>