<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

         <string name="tool_scissors">
        Used for tasks such as cutting away clothing to expose injured areas
             to be able to treat the wounds better. But most commonly used for cutting gauze
             or adhesive bandages to an appropriate length.

        </string>

    <string name="tool_adhesive_bandage">
       Also known as plaster, it is a small medical dressing used for injuries not serious
        enough to require a full-size bandage.

        </string>

    <string name="tool_cotton">
       For medical purposes, cotton pads are used to stop
    or prevent bleeding from minor punctures such as
    injections or venipuncture.usually used for cleaning wounds
        and for padding and protection, not really for applying onto open wounds as
        the free fibres can break away and stay in the wound

        </string>


    <string name="tool_gauze">
      Used for absorbing fluids, as well as dressing and protecting wounds. Sterile gauze
        act as a barrier to prevent contaminants from entering any wound area that it covers
        and absorbs ny blood or fluid that seeps out of the wound.

        </string>

    <string name="tool_gloves">
      Medical gloves are an essential everyday item for all
        healthcare professionals working in a healthcare environment.  Gloves not only protect the wearer
        but they also create a safety zone for both healthcare providers and patients.
        All medical gloves are disposable, single-use items and they are available in a variety of different
        materials, such as Latex, Nitrile Rubber, Vinyl, and Neoprene.

        </string>


    <string name="tool_elastic">
      Multi-purpose bandages for sprains, strains and hard-to-bandage areas.
        For both types of injuries, the first aid equipment of choice is elastic bandages.
        Elastic bandages reduce blood flow to the injured area by providing even and localized pressure consequently
        limiting swelling. These types bandages can also be used to stabilize splints.

        </string>

    <string name="tool_adhesive_tape">
     Different adhesive tapes have different uses due to the properties they have. They are mainly used for holding dressing in place.
        Zinc Oxide tape is used for immobilisation of joints. Elasticated Adhesive
        Bandages (EAB) are regularly used to provide flexible support. Non woven paper tape for dressing retention.
        Easily tearable breathable plastic tape for dressing retention.
        For holding dressings in place in a moist environment.
        </string>


    <string name="tool_soap">
    Mild soap used to gently clean the area around the wound.
        It kills any pathogenic microbe
        that my cause infection to the wound.
        </string>


    <string name="tool_tweezer">
     Tweezers are an important tool to have in any first aid kit
        regardless of how basic your kit is. Tweezers can be used to remove debris such as glass, dirt,
        or splinters from a wound.
        They can also be used to remove stingers left behind by bees.
        </string>

    <string name="tool_thermometer">
    A first-aid kit should contain a thermometer to measure body temperature.
        An oral digital thermometer is probably the best choice.
        Digital thermometers used in the ear are more accurate but also more expensive.
        Fever can be relieved with paracetamol or ibuprofen.
        </string>



</resources>