<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="array_heat_problem">
        <item>Minor Burns and Scalds</item>
        <item>Electric Burns</item>
        <item>Chemical Burns</item>
        <item>Surn Burns</item>
        <item>Hypothermia</item>
    </string-array>


    //burns and scalds
    <string name="burn_priority_content">
   &#8226;Stop the burning process as quickly as possible.\n
&#8226;Relieve pain and swelling.\n
&#8226;Prevent infection of the injured area.
 </string>
    <string name="burn_treatment_content">

 &#8226;Stop the burning process as soon as possible but be careful not to put yourself at risk of being burnt.\n\n
 &#8226;Help the victim remove any clothing or jewelry near the burnt area of the skin
        quickly and gently before the area swells, however DO NOT try to
        remove anything that is stuck to the burnt skin.\n\n
 &#8226;Cool the burn with cool/lukewarm water for 10-20 minutes or until the pain eases.
        This can be done by holding the burned area under cool running water or applying a
        clan towel damped with tap water. NEVER use ice r greasy substance such as butter.\n\n
 &#8226;Do not break the small blisters and if they break, clean them with mild soap and clean water.
        Apply antibiotic ointment and cover it with nonstick gauze bandage.\n\n
 &#8226;Apply moisturizer such as gel or aloe vera lotion which may provide relief.\n\n
 &#8226;You can cover the burn with a cling film (a thin plastic film), put the film in a layer
        over the burn rather than wrapping it around the limb.
        A clean plastic bag can be used for burns on your hand.\n\n
 &#8226;If necessary, give the victim over-the-counter pain relievers such as ibuprofen to relieve from pain.\n\n
 &#8226;The victim should get tetanus booster shot if the date of last shot given is more than 10 years.\n\n

        <b>For major burns:\n\n</b>

&#8226;Do not immerse large severe burns in cold water as this cold may cause a serious loss in body heat or
        a medical shock (decreased blood flow).\n
&#8226;You can keep the victim warm by using a blanket or layer of clothing but avoid putting it around the burned area.\n
&#8226;Cover the burned area using a cool moist bandage or a clean cloth.\n\n

        <b>When to seek for medical help:\n\n</b>


&#8226;If the burns cover large section of the victim\'s body and if you notice signs of infection such as redness,
        swelling, increased pain and oozing from the burned area.\n
&#8226;If the victim develops large blisters.\n
    </string>



    <string name="burn_degree">
  <u>Degree of Burns</u>
 </string>

    <string name="burn_degree_content">

 <b>  First Degree\n</b>
&#8226;It is the least serious degree of burn which are treated as minor burns.\n
&#8226;It only involves the outer layer of the ski and may cause redness, swelling and pain.\n
&#8226;Seek for urgent medical help it it involves much of hands, face, buttocks, feet, groin or a major joint.\n\n

<b>Second Degree\n</b>
&#8226;It is more serious than the first degree burn and may cause pain, blisters, swelling red or white skin.\n
&#8226;If the burn is no longer than 7.6 centimeters treat it as minor as minor burn but
        if it covers sections of the body such as hands, face, buttocks,
        feet, groin or major joint, then seek urgent medical help.\n\n


<b>Third Degree\n</b>
&#8226;It is the most serious of the three degrees of burns because it involves all layers of the skin and the fat beneath.\n
&#8226;Bones and muscles may also be affected by the burn.\n
&#8226;The area burned may be charred black or white and the victim may have breathing complications
        or carbon monoxide poisoning if smoke inhalation occurred.\n
&#8226;Seek for urgent medical help.\n\n\n
    </string>



    //Electrical burns
    <string name="electrical_priority_content">
  &#8226; Cut off supply of electric power if possible.\n
  &#8226;Treat the burns and shock.\n
  &#8226;Urgently transfer the victim to a hospital.
 </string>

    <string name="electrical_treatment_content">

 &#8226; <b>DO NOT</b> touch the victim unless the source of electricity is turned off and if not possible,
        move the victim away from the electric source by:\n\n
&#8226;First ensuring you stand on a dry insulator surface such as rubber doormat or a pile of papers.
        Ensure you are not standing in or near water.\n\n
&#8226;Using a dry non-conducting object made of plastic or woog such as broom handle,
        push the victim away from the electric source.\n\n
&#8226;Begin <b>CPR</b> if the person does not show signs of circulation such as breathing, coughing or movement.\n\n
&#8226;Try to prevent the victim from becoming chilled.\n\n
&#8226;Cover any burned areas with sterile gauze bandage, if available or clean cloth.
        Never use blankets to cover the burned area because loose fibres can stick to the burns.\n\n
&#8226;Seek for medical help if the victim has: Breathing complications, Cardiac arrest,
        Loss of consciousness, Muscle pain and Contractions.\n\n\n

 </string>



    //Chemical burns
    <string name="chemical_priority_content">
&#8226; Remove the harmful chemical substance.\n
&#8226;Transfer the victim to a hospital.

 </string>

    <string name="chemical_treatment_content">
 &#8226;Wear gloves in order to protect yourself and remove the chemical causing the burn.\n\n
&#8226;Remove the contaminated clothing or jewellery to prevent further damage by the chemical substance.\n\n
&#8226;Rinse the burn immediately by running a steady stream of cool water over the burn for about ten minutes or more.\n\n
&#8226;Loosely apply a bandage.\n\n
&#8226;Seek for medical help.\n\n\n

 </string>


    //Sun burns
    <string name="sun_recognition_content">
 &#8226;Pain in the area of the burn.\n
 &#8226;Reddened/ Pinked skin.\n
 &#8226;Blistering of the affected skin.\n
 &#8226;Skin that feel warm or hot to the touch.\n
    &#8226; <b>If SEVERE</b> headaches, fever and fatigue is felt.\n

 </string>

    <string name="sun_treatment_content">
  &#8226;Help the victim to move into the shade or indoors.\n
 &#8226;Apply a clean towel dampened with cool tap water on the victim\'s skin or advice the person to take a cool shower.\n\n
 &#8226;Apply moisturizer such as aloe vera lotion or gel which will provide relief.\n\n
  &#8226;<b>DO NOT</b> break the blisters and if the blisters break, wash the area with mild soap and water
        then apply an antibiotic ointment ans cover with nonstick gauze bandage.\n\n
 &#8226;If the burns are severe causing effects such as extreme pain, headache or chills, seek for medical help.\n\n\n

 </string>



    //Hypothermia
    <string name="hypothermia_recognition_content">
 &#8226;Shivering.\n
&#8226;Cold and pale dry skin.\n
&#8226;Apathy.\n
&#8226;Impaired consciousness.\n
&#8226;Slow shallow breathing.\n
&#8226;Slow and weak pulse.\n
&#8226;Slurred speech.\n
&#8226;Drowsiness and very low energy.

 </string>

    <string name="hypothermia_treatment_content">
 &#8226;Move the person indoors out of the cold and if not possible, shield him/her
        against wind especially around head and neck.\n\n
&#8226;Insulate the person from cold ground.\n\n
&#8226;Remove wet clothing and replace with warm and dry blankets or coats.\n\n
&#8226;Give the person warm sweet non-alcoholic drink.\n\n
&#8226;Begin CPR if the person does not show signs of life such as breathing.\n\n\n

 </string>


</resources>