<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="array_poison_problem">
        <item>Food Poisoning</item>
        <item>Swallowed Poison</item>
        <item>Alcohol Poisoning</item>
    </string-array>


    <string name="food_about_content">
Food poisoning is an illness caused by eating food contaminated
        by bacteria, fungi, virus or other toxins.
    </string>

    <string name="food_recognition_content">
       &#8226;Nausea (Feeling sick).\n
       &#8226;Vomiting.\n
       &#8226;Abdominal pain and stomach cramps.\n
       &#8226;Loss of appetite.\n
       &#8226;Diarrhea which contain mucus or blood.\n
       &#8226;Fever.\n
       &#8226;Lack of energy and weakness.\n
       &#8226;Chills and aching muscles.\n
       &#8226;Headache.
</string>

    <string name="food_explain_content">
     <u> When to immediately seek for medical help.</u>
    </string>

    <string name="food_content">
      &#8226;When the patient has a racing or skipping heartbeat.\n\n
      &#8226;When the patient\'s stool has a lot of blood in it (it\'s black or maroon).\n\n
      &#8226;If the patient is sick from mushrooms, shellfish or canned items,
        this is because toxins from these foods can have  potentially dangerous effects.
</string>

    <string name="food_treatment_content">
    &#8226;When to immediately seek for medical help.Drinck clear fluids such as water,
        starting with small sips and gradually drink more.\n\n
&#8226;Avoid solid foods until vomiting stops after which eat light , bland food such as bananas, bread or rice.\n\n
&#8226;DO NOT eat fried, greasy, spicy or sweet food since they can cause more vomiting and nausea.\n\n
&#8226;If vomiting lasts more than 24 hours, drink an oral rehydration solution.\n\n
&#8226;Take a table spoon of honey with few drops of ginger juice to reduce inflammation and pain.\n\n
&#8226;Taking basil juice leaves early in the morning on an empty stomach will improve tour digestion.\n\n
&#8226;Do not take over the counter anti-nausea or anti-diarrhea medication without consulting a doctor,
        since it may interfere with the natural healing process and even make the diarrhea worse.
</string>

    <string name="food_doctor">
    <u> When to contact a doctor:</u>
</string>

    <string name="food_doctor_content">
     Contact a doctor if the following symptoms persists for more than three days:\n
    &#8226;Fever.\n
    &#8226;Bloody diarrhea.\n
    &#8226;Severe belly pain.\n
     &#8226;Prolonged or bloody vomiting.\n
    &#8226;If the patient exhibits signs of dehydration e.g. dizziness, fatigue and dry mouth.\n\n
   </string>


    //swallowed poison

    <string name="swallowed_about_content">
    Poisoning occurs when any substance interferes with normal functioning
        of the body after it has been swallowed, injected, inhaled or absorbed.
    </string>

    <string name="swallowed_recognition_content">
        General symptoms of poisoning include:\n
 &#8226;Dizziness and general body weakness.\n
 &#8226;Breathing difficulties.\n
 &#8226;Drowsiness or loss consciousness.\n
 &#8226;Seizures.\n
 &#8226;Nausea.\n
 &#8226;Abnormal skin e.g. occurrence of skin rash.\n
 &#8226;Stomach pain.\n
 &#8226;Producing more saliva than normal.\n
 &#8226;Blue lips and skin.\n
 &#8226;Blurred vision.\n
 &#8226;Mental confusion.\n
 &#8226;In severe cases it could lead to a coma.
    </string>


    <string name="swallowed_treatment_content">
&#8226;If conscious, ask the casualty what they have swallowed, the quantity and when.\n\n
&#8226;Call your local emergency number immediately for help and tell them as much information as possible.\n\n
&#8226;Remove any substance remaining in the casualty\'s mouth.\n\n
&#8226;If the suspected poison container is in place, read the label and follow instructions for accidental poisoning.\n\n
        &#8226;<b>DO NOT</b> attempt to make the casualty vomit the substance because it can cause further damage, but if they vomit naturally,
        put some of their vomit in to a container and give I to the ambulance team.\n\n
&#8226;Collect the pill bottles or containers with labels and any other info concerning
        the poison and send it along with the emergency team, since this will help
        the medics have appropriate treatment.\n\n
&#8226;Begin CPR if the person becomes unconscious (please refer to the steps in performing CPR in the app).\n\n
    </string>



    //Alcohol poison

    <string name="alcohol_about_content">
   Alcohol poisoning is a serious consequence of drinking large amounts of alcohol within a short time.
        It may affect your breathing, heart rate, gag reflex, body temperature and may even lead to a coma and death.\n
It can also occur when a person accidentally drink mhousehold products that contain alcohol.
    </string>

    <string name="alcohol_recognition_content">
     &#8226;Confusion.\n
&#8226;Slow and irregular breathing.\n
&#8226;Vomiting.\n
&#8226;Seizures.\n
&#8226;Pale skin.\n
&#8226;Low body temperatures.\n
&#8226;Unconscious or can be conscious but unresponsive (Stupor).
    </string>


    <string name="alcohol_treatment_content">
&#8226;Call your local emergency number immediately and <b>NEVER</b> assume that the person will sleep off alcohol poisoning.\n\n
&#8226;If aware provide info to the emergency personnel of the kind, amount and the time the person drank the alcohol.\n\n
        &#8226;While waiting for help, <b>DO NOT</b> try to make the patient vomit because this could make them choke.\n\n
&#8226;If the victim is vomiting, keep them sitting up and if they must lie down, ensure to turn
        their head to the side since this helps to prevent chocking.\n\n
&#8226;If the person is conscious, it is advisable to give them
        lots of water since this will help flush alcohol from their system.
        DO NOT give them black coffee since it does not help to flush alcohol from their system.\n\n
&#8226;Place a blanket or coat over the patient to help them keep warm.\n\n
&#8226;Try to keep the person awake to prevent loss of consciousness.\n\n
&#8226;Begin CPR if the patient become unconscious (please refer to the steps in performing CPR in the app).\n\n
    </string>









</resources>