<resources>
    <string name="app_name">TibaSmart</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Android Studio</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">android.studio@android.com</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>


    <string name="provine_name">Select your Province</string>

    <string name="err_email">Invalid email</string>

    <string name="err_password_confirmation">
     The passwords do not match
    </string>


    <string-array name="array_province_name">
        <item>Nairobi</item>
        <item>Rift valley</item>
        <item>Central</item>
        <item>Nyanza</item>
        <item>Western</item>
        <item>Eastern</item>
        <item>Coast</item>
        <item>North Eastern</item>
    </string-array>


    <string name="blood_group">Select Blood Group</string>
    <string-array name="array_blood_group">
        <item>A</item>
        <item>B</item>
        <item>AB</item>
        <item>O</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="rhesus">Select Rhesus Type</string>
    <string-array name="array_rhesus">
        <item>Rhesus +ve</item>
        <item>Rhesus -ve</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="gender">Select Gender</string>
    <string-array name="array_gender">
        <item>Male</item>
        <item>Female</item>

    </string-array>
    <string name="title_activity_driver_maps">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>


    //Activity 2- problems category from main activity cardviews

    <string-array name="array_circulatory_problem">
        <item>Heart Attack</item>
        <item>Angina Pectoris</item>
        <item>Fainting</item>
        <item>Shock</item>
    </string-array>


    //universal Titles
    <string name="title_about"><u>About</u></string>
    <string name="title_recognition"><u>Recognition</u> </string>
    <string name="title_treatment"><u>Treatment</u></string>


    //heart attack contents
    <string name="heart_about">
        A heart attack occurs when the flow of blood rich in oxygen, to a section of heart muscle is blocked.
    </string>

    <string name="heart_recognition">
        &#8226;Persistent central chest pain that spread to\n the left arm and jaw.\n
        &#8226;Sudden fainting and dizziness.\n
        &#8226;Shortness of breath or difficulty in breathing.\n
        &#8226;Profuse sweating.\n
        &#8226;Rapid or irregular heartbeats.\n
        &#8226;The patient may suddenly collapse.\n
        &#8226;Nausea.
    </string>

    <string name="heart_treatment">
        &#8226;Encourage the patient to rest and make him or her as comfortable as possible to ease the
        strain on his or her heart.\n\n
        &#8226;A half sitting position with the patient\'s head and shoulders well
        supported and knees bent is always the best.\n\n
        &#8226;Call for an ambulance
        and state that you suspect it to be a heart attack.\n\n
        &#8226;If the patient is not allergic to aspirin and is fully conscious, give him or her 300 mg asprin
        tablet and advice him or her to chew it slowly.\n\n
        &#8226;Begin CPR if the person is unconscious, please
        refer to the steps in performing CPR in the app.\n
    </string>

    //agina attack contents
    <string name="agina_about">
       Angina is a chestpain that occurs when the blood supply to heart muscles is restricted. It
        usually occurs due to hardening or narrowing of heart arteries.</string>

    <string name="title_agina_types">
      <u>Types of Angina</u>
    </string>

    <string name="agina_types">
        <u>Stable-</u> Attacks are brought by
        triggers such as exercise but improves with medication and rest.
        It is not life threatening on its own.\n\n
        <u>Unstable-</u> Attacks are unpredictable and continue despite resting. It should be regarded as
        a medical emergency as it indicates the functioning
        of the heart has suddenly deteroriated.

    </string>


    <string name="agina_recognition">
        &#8226;Pain easing with rest.\n
        &#8226;Central chest pain spreading to the jaw.\n
        &#8226;Feeling of anxiety.\n
        &#8226;Profuse sweating.\n
        &#8226;Dizziness.\n
        &#8226;Shortness of breath.\n
        &#8226;Nausea and fatigue.
    </string>

    <string name="agina_treatment">
        &#8226;Advice the patient to stop any activity he
        or she is engaged in and sit down straight away.\n\n
        &#8226;Reassure them and make
        them comfortable as this will help ease the pain.\n\n
        &#8226;Advice the patient
        to take antiAngina medication e.g. aerosol spray or tablet.\n\n
        &#8226;If the pain subsides
        (In case of stable Angina) the patient
        can resume to his or her activities.\n\n
        &#8226;If the pain persists or resumes,
        suspect heart attack and call for an ambulance.\n
    </string>


    //fainting contents

    <string name="faint_about">
       Fainting also known as syncope, is the sudden and temporary loss of
        consciousness and posture caused by decrease inflow of blood rich in oxygen to the brain.
    </string>

    <string name="faint_recognition">
        &#8226;Dizziness or light headedness.\n
        &#8226;Rapid heartbeat or pulse.\n
        &#8226;Burled vision.\n
        &#8226;Profuse sweating.\n
        &#8226;Headache.\n
        &#8226;Nausea.\n
        &#8226;Ringing in the ears.\n
        &#8226;The patient may suddenly collapse.
    </string>

    <string name="faint_treatment">
        &#8226;When the patient feels faint, advise him to lie down in his back,
        rise his legs at least 10 inches (30cm) or support his ankles on your.\n\n
        &#8226;A half sitting position with the patient\'s head and shoulders well
        supported and knees bent is always the best
        shoulders since this improves blood circulation to the brain.\n\n
        &#8226;Make sure the casualty has plenty of
        fresh air by opening windows and asking any bystanders to stay clear.\n\n
        &#8226;As he recovers reassure him or her and help him or her sit up gradually.\n\n
        &#8226;If the patient starts feeling faint again, advice him or her to lie down
        again and raise and support his legs until he recovers fully.\n\n
        &#8226;To reduce the chance of fainting again, don\'t get the person up too quickly.\n\n
        &#8226;If the patient doesn\'t regain consciousness within
        one minute, call your local emergency number.\n\n
         &#8226;Begin CPR if the person does not show any signs of circulation such as breathing,
        coughing or movement, please refer to the steps in performing CPR in the app.\n\n


    </string>

    //shock contents

    <string name="shock_about">
       Shock is a life threatening condition, that occurs
        when you do not have enough blood circulating around your body,
        and caused by fators such as uncontrolled bleeding, severe burns and spinal injury.</string>

    <string name="title_shock_types">
      <u>Types of Shock</u>
    </string>

    <string name="shock_types">
     Some of the types include:\n\n
    <u>Hypovolaemic:</u> It occurs when there is no enough blood volume caused by
        excessive bleeding, dehydration or severe burns.\n\n
        <u>Nuerogenic:</u> It occurs when there is damage on a person\'s
        spine which in turn damages the nerves that control the width of the blood vessels.\n\n
        <u>Cardiogenic:</u> It occurs when the heart cannot effectively pump blood
        around the body caused by heart attack and other heart diseases.\n\n
        <u>Septic-</u> Caused by an infection which causes blood vessels to expand hence
        cause a drop in the blood pressure.
    </string>


    <string name="shock_recognition">
        &#8226;Dizziness or light headedness.\n
        &#8226;Rapid heartbeat or pulse.\n
        &#8226;Difficulty in breathing and anxiety.\n
        &#8226;Confusion and disorientation.\n
        &#8226;Pale, cold, clammy skin.\n
        &#8226;Nausea and vomiting.\n
        &#8226;Low urine output or dark urine.\n
        &#8226;Thirst or a dry mouth.\n
        &#8226;Unconsciousness.
    </string>

    <string name="shock_treatment">
        &#8226;If the patient is conscious,
        lie him down and keep him warm and comfortable.\n\n
        &#8226;Loosen his tight clothing.\n\n
        &#8226;If possible, raise the patient\'s legs slightly above the level of their torso and head.
        If you suspect spinal injury or if raising the legs cause further pain, then DO NOT raise them.\n\n
        &#8226;Manage any signs of external bleeding e.g. by firm pressing a clean cloth on the wound.\n\n
        &#8226;DO NOT give the person anything to eat or drink even if they are thirsty.\n\n
        &#8226;Reassure the person and advice hem to rest or stay still as you await the ambulance to arrive.\n\n

    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_ambulance__location">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_street_view">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_directions_api">Map</string>


</resources>
